<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="820">
  <number>0</number>
  <name>Welcome to Build a Lesson with Open Educational Resources (OER)</name>
  <summary>&lt;p id="yui_3_13_0_2_1403104360292_1239" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231; font-size: 13px;"&gt;The purpose of this course is to help teachers with experience in Moodle develop a comprehensive online lesson using OER to deliver instruction. You will learn to take content from your lesson plan and pair it up with the appropriate Moodle resources or activities. Also, because you are assigned as the editing teacher feel free to add, delete, hide or change any of the content provided in this course shell. The screencast below provides more information on the course and how you can use it. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;object width="100%" height="183"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="//www.youtube.com/v/Wp9XJZBYW38?hl=en_US&amp;amp;version=3&amp;amp;rel=0" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;embed width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/v/Wp9XJZBYW38?hl=en_US&amp;amp;version=3&amp;amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Modules 2-4 offer screen casts and sample Moodle Resources and Activities showing how a particular WIPPEA lesson plan was constructed with different instructional delivery methods in mind. If you are interested in “flipped teaching” with an online component, take a look at the “Flipped Delivery Model” below. Other models presented show taking the same lesson and having learners complete the work on their own (self-study) or with teacher guidance (facilitated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>2933,2935,2934</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availablefrom>0</availablefrom>
  <availableuntil>0</availableuntil>
  <showavailability>0</showavailability>
  <groupingid>0</groupingid>
</section>